Silva, Murillo

H-40 Street - Vera Cruz - Aparecida de Goiania murillov.dev@gmail.com | +55 62 983-196-600 www.linkedin.com/in/murillo-vieira

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Having about 4 years of experience in the field as a Frontend and Fullstack developer, I've worked on important projects in every phase of the software development lifecycle, from business requirements collection to project delivery. Throught the code, I always try to add value to the company being aware of the company's perspectives and goals.

CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Led a team of 4 Frontend developers and increased the amount of tasks delivered by the team by 25% per Sprint
- 2. Incremented the developers productivity by 10% by creating automated tools and by writing detailed documentation
- 3. Identified performance issues an cut down the screen render time by four times, also reducing overfetch
- 4. Given talks to a large community. Also helped 5 other people from coding basics to mid-level
- 5. Had participate of programming marathons at college and have won one local contest among 10 another teams

CAREER HISTORY

Fullstack Developer at Nectar CRM

Biggest CRM company in Goiás

Dec 2018 – Present • 9 mos

- Cooperated on the development of the main application, helping to implement TDD
- Shaped the CRM app with the new UX/UI set
- Improved the Backoffice webapp of the company
- Developed new functionalities into the software

Fullstack Developer at Nussa Sistemas

Jun 2015 – Present • 4 years, 3 mos

- Freelancer web developer, mobile apps, PWAs and websites
- Tech Stacks: Ionic 2+, MEAN, MERN, PHP (Wordpress), Firebase
- Experience in data consumption optimization

Some projects I worked for Nussa Sistemas were: mobile app for package delivery, PWA for medical congresses, webapp with daily liturgy for Goiânia Archdiocese.

Frontend Developer at Actuar

Leading provider of academic software in Brazil Jul 2017 – Dec 2018 • 1 yr 6 mos

Actuar is a company which focus on proving technology to gyms and web payment. As of August 2018, the company had approximately 2.000 throughout Brazil, more than 15.000 users from physic evaluation free webapp and thousands from TREI.NO app in Brazil and abroad. In 18 months I was able to:

- Lead a team of developers applying SCRUM and working on the development of an ERP focused on gyms management and crossfit boxes
- Estimate the effort for new demands and performed verification of the artifacts of software engineering such as requirements, design, implementation and testing
- Develop the math logic for payment methods, discounts and bonus
- Create webcomponent for scheduling software implantation and support inspection visits
- Give maintenance on a training app. Made responsive blogs and webpages for the company, also performing SEO

Internship Software Developer at Meta

Feb 2017 – Jul 2017 • 6 mos

MetaTecnologia is a company with over 12 years of experience computerizing mobile phone shops. There I worked on the improvement of a product to control financial of mobile phone stores, and payment system integration to federal government. I was a Fullstack developer, I studied and handled JAVA and MongoDB on backend and JSP, HTML, Bootstrap and CSS for frontend.

EDUCATION

University Degree

2015 - 2018

Universidade Federal de Goias

Bachelor of Computer Information Systems

Having also studied Computer Science since 2009, which included Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Compilers, Operating Systems, Algorithms and its Complexity.

Certificates

React Native with NodeJS and Firebase (28h); MERN Stack, Frontend to Backend (12h); Agile management with SCRUM (10h); Complete Javascript 2018 - Fundamentals to Master (35h); Web Design for Web Developers: UI/UX for Websites and Mobile (8h);

SKILLS & ADDITIONAL INFORMATION



Also a burger lover and a charismatic pianist

INTERESTS

- Use data science to expand the business
- Grow as a developer and bring life to great ideas
- Help people to use programming concepts and invent more

You can check out more at my personal website:

https://murilloves.github.io/dev/